[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：输入可观测数据。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Enter observables.
现在，请理解Observable并不是JavaScript的保证。
Now, understand that Observables are not a guarantee for JavaScript.
现在它们在用户地库中实现，并且
Right now they are implemented in user-land libraries, and
有一项建议是将可观测数据放在该语言中。
there is a proposal for Observables to land in the language.
在某种程度上，
At some point,
有一种强烈的感觉，他们可能会在ES7的时间框架内着陆。
there was a strong feeling that they might land in the ES7 time frame.
据我所知，我认为这不会在ES7中发生，
As far as I'm aware, I don't think that's actually gonna happen in the ES7,
意思是ES2016。
meaning ES2016.
因为就我今天所知，我认为这个功能被切断了
Because as far as I'm aware as of today, I think the feature cut off for
ES2016就像是下个月。
ES2016 is like next month.
所以观察到的是一条很好的道路，我们有很好的机会
So Observables are on a good path and there's a pretty good chance we're going
在语言中自然地得到这样的东西。
to get something like this natively in the language.
只是可能不是下个月。
It just might not be next month.
所以可能会更远一点。
So it might be a little bit further off.
这意味着我们将要从可观察到的东西中学到的东西，
And that means that what we're about to learn with Observables,
我们基于特定库实现的语义进行学习。
we're learning based upon the semantics of a particular library implementation.
我们并没有很好的意识到他们将会是一个本地人
We don't have a very good sense of exactly what they're going to be from a native
原始的视角，就像我们对承诺做的那样。
primitive perspective, like we did with promises.
所以这里需要注意的是，我们将要讨论的内容是主题
So the caveat here is the sorts of stuff that we're about to talk about is subject
对于某些流量，从现在到现在这段时间内，它会受到一些进化的影响
to some flux, it's subject to some evolution between now and the time that
一些最终的标准陆地观测值可能最终会被称为不同的东西。
some final standard lands Observables may end up being called something different.
他们可能有不同的API，谁知道呢，但是
They might have a different looking API, who knows, but
现在外面有一个很好的图书馆
right now there's a pretty good library out there for
Observables，它叫做RXJ.S，这是我们的JavaScript库，实际上是
Observables and it's called RX J.S. that's our JavaScript library it's actually
rx是库读取反应性扩展的名称。
RX is the name of the library read reactive extensions.
它是由微软的聪明人制作的，而且
It's made by the folks really smart folks at Microsoft, and
他们把它移植成了十几种或几十种不同的语言。
they've ported it to like a dozen or a couple dozen different languages.
所以RXJS是JavaScript端口。
So RXJS is the JavaScript port.
在C.Sharp
It's in C. Sharp,
我认为这是最初的版本，它在Java中，在其他几种语言中。
I think that's the original one, it's in Java, it's in several other languages.
所以从一致性的角度看这很好，
So it's nice from the consistency perspective,
无论您使用的是哪种语言，可能都有一个RX库。
whatever language you work in there's probably an RX library for it.
一旦你学会了
Once you learn it,
一旦你可以在很多地方使用它，那就很好了。
once you're gonna be able to use it in lots of places that's good.
但是要理解什么是可观察的，再一次从概念的角度来看，
But to understand what an observable is, again from a conceptual perspective,
看，这就是我一直以来的教学方式，我会先教你API，
see this is how I always teach, I'm gonna teach you the API first,
我想教你概念。
I wanna teach you the conceptuals.
所以让我们来谈谈电子表格。
So let's talk about spreadsheets.
每个人都喜欢电子表格，对吧？
Everybody loves spreadsheets, right?
我刚刚在Google Images上发现了一些随机的电子表格图像
I just found some random spreadsheet image on Google Images,
因为我自己没有什么好的。
cuz I don't have any good ones to take of my own.
我不知道电子表格是什么，但很清楚
I don't know what the spreadsheet is, but it's pretty clear
这个电子表格说明了我想要理解的概念。
that this spreadsheet is illustrating the concept that I want to get across.
顺便说一下，这个比喻并不是我独有的。
By the way, this metaphor is not unique to me.
所以我从别人那里听到了这句话。
So I've heard this from others.
我只是认为这是一个特别好的开始。
I just think it's a particularly good one to start with.
而Observable有点像电子表格中计算字段的链。
And observable is kind of like a chain of calculated fields in a spreadsheet.
因此，您知道，在电子表格中，可以在字段中包含数据。
So you know in spreadsheets you can have data in a field.
但也可以有一个字段，它是一个计算字段。
But you can also have a field, which is a calculated field.
它是根据其他领域的数据计算出来的。
It's calculated based upon the data that's in some other field.
所以C1可能有数字10，C2，
So C1 might have the number ten in it, and C2,
就在下面，它可能是任何值乘以2。
right below it might be whatever the values in there times two.
所以当我键入10，然后我一按Enter，这个字段立即显示20。
So when I type in 10, then as soon as I hit enter, immediately this field says 20.
我可能在这里有另一个字段，我可能有D13，它说，
And I might have another field over here, I might have D13 that says,
D13是对C2中的任何东西的三次计算。
D13 is the calculation of three times whatever's in C2.
所以我把这个改为20，C1变成20，
So I changed this to 20, C1 becomes 20,
C2变成40，D13变成120，对吗？
C2 becomes 40, and D13 becomes 120, right?
你看到计算链是数据流了吗？
Do you see that the calculation chain is a flow of data?
我们正在设置从原始源位置到
We're setting up a flow of data from an original source location to
所有这些不同的地方，我们正在用这些数据做一些事情。
all these different places, where we're doing something with that data.
我们在计算一些东西。
We're calculating something.
我们正在订阅并响应这些数据。
We're subscribing to and responding to that data.
这就是反应式编程概念的起源。
That's the genesis of this notion of reactive programming.
当我们考虑反应式编程时，它是说，
When we think about reactive programming it is to say,
我的数据来源有些来源。
the source of my data some of that source.
但是数据一旦我得到那个事件，它将经历一系列的步骤和
But the data once I get that event, it's going to go through a series of steps and
其中一些步骤将是直接的，就像响应
some of those steps are going to be direct like responsive just
计算一些东西，其中一些可能是异步步骤。
calculate something and some of them might be asynchronous steps.
当您更改电子表格时，对经过电子表格的数据的计算
The calculation of the data that goes through the spreadsheet as you change one
价值，即使它对我们来说是立竿见影的。
value, even though it looks immediate to us.
每一步都必须更新所有字段，然后更新所有字段和
Each step it has to update all the fields and then update all the fields and
然后更新所有字段，因此如果您愿意的话，会有一些传播延迟。
then update all the fields, so there is some propagation delay if you will.
但我们可以考虑将可观察的或相当于反应性的编程作为一种方式
But we can think about an observable or rather reactive programming as a way to
对一侧的数据进行建模，即来自生产者的数据。
model a piece of data coming in one side, that's from the producer.
事件发射器，如果您愿意，从一侧进入，并且
The event emitter, if you will, coming in one side, and
在系统中传播其方式所需的所有步骤。
all the steps that it takes to propagate its way through a system.
这是一种数据流机制，并且
It's a data flow mechanism, and
数据流机制是从头开始构建的，以响应事件。
data flow mechanisms are built from the ground up to respond to events.
所以如果我们有一个通风口导向的系统，
So if we've got a vent oriented systems,
这对我们来说可能是一个非常好的抽象。
this might be a really good abstraction for us.
每个人都在概念上追随我的来历吗。
Is everybody following where I'm coming from conceptually.
所以我们会把它归结为你。
So we'll boil this down for you.
Observable是挂在事件源上的适配器
An observable is an adapter hooked onto an event source
每当有新的事件发生时，这就产生了一种承诺。
that produces a promise, every time a new event comes through.
但它是以单独的方式这样做的，在那里我可以设置我的事件源。
But it does so in that separate way, where I can set up my event source.
和我的位置完全不同的一部分，我可以声明性地说，
And an entirely different part of my location, I can declaratively say,
我的数据流是什么？
what's my data flow?
我不需要像我们在其他例子中所做的那样把两者混为一谈，
I don't have to conflate the two like we're doing in those other examples,
我把承诺放在活动里面的地方。
where I put the promise inside of the event thing.
我有一个表示数据源的观察体，我可以订阅它
I have an observable that represents my data source and I can subscribe to that
可以在我系统的一个或多个其他位置以完全独立的方式观察到。
observable in one or more other locations of my system in an entirely separate way.
它会神奇地处理这一切
And it's going to magically take care of all that
创造承诺的桥梁和鸿沟为我们。
creation of promises in the bridge and the gap for us.
所以这是编程的一种方式来表示我们可以直观地思考的东西，或者
So it's a way in programming to represent what we can visually think about, or
从电子表格概念上考虑。
conceptually think about from a spreadsheet.
我们可以将这些不同字段中的每一个表示为不同的步骤
We can represent each one of those different fields as a different step
在对一个可观察到的事物的一系列反应中。
in a chain of response to an observable.
下面是我们RxJS中一些代码的快速示例，
So here's a quick example of some code from our RxJS,
您会注意到，您使用Rx.Observable.fromEvent创建了一个Observable。
you'll notice that you create an observable using Rx.Observable.fromEvent.
这是他们提供的众多公用事业之一，其设置方式是，
That's one of their many utilities they provide and the way it's set up is,
它接受黎明元素和事件名称，它自动挂钩事件名称
it takes the dawn elements an event name it automatically hooks the event name
到黎明元素，并且每次其中一个事件发生时
to the dawn element and every time one of those events fires
它将另一条数据通过链，通过可观察到的。
it pumps another piece of data through the chain, through the observable.
这就是我们如何从事件中创建可观察的。
So that's how we create an observable from an event.
大约有十几种不同的方法来使一个可观察的。
There's about a dozen or so different ways to make an observable.
您可以通过将其附加到事件来创建一个。
You can make one by attaching it to an event.
你可以让一个普通的、简单的可观察到，你要手动地把一些数据
You can make a plain old simple observable that you manually are gonna put some data
通过，您可以从网站附加它，
through, you can attach it from a website,
我的意思是有很多不同的方法来制作可观察的东西。
I mean there's a lot of different ways to make observables.
但我在一号线上做了一个可观察到的东西，在我系统的一个完全不同的部分。
But I make an observable on line one, in an entirely different part of my system.
我可以声明所有这些步骤是什么，
I can declare what all those steps are,
我的电子表格中所有字段的计算是什么样子的。
what all the calculations of the fields in my spreadsheet look like.
基本上，我制作了数据流的声明性链。
Basically, I make a declarative chain of the data flow.
因此，每次从DOM事件进入事件时，每次我单击按钮
So every time an event comes in from the DOM event, every time I click on a button
这是一段数据进来，它将通过这条链流动。
that's a piece of data coming in and it's going to flow through this chain.
现在，我们有一些看起来很熟悉的实用程序，就像地图一样。
Now, we have utilities that look familiar to us like map.
同步意义上的map遍历了整个数组的值。
Map in the synchronous sense went over a whole array of the values.
每次有新数据时，就会调用异步事件中的映射
Map in the asynchronous event is just invoked every time a new piece of data
出现了。
comes along.
因此，您可以实际将事件流看作一个永不结束的数组。
So you can actually think about an event stream as a never ending array.
并且我们可以在不同的时间执行相同类型的列表操作
And we can perform the same sorts of list operations across time
我们会一起做的事。
that we would do all together.
这就是为什么对我们来说理解地图和归约以及
That's why it was important for us to understand maps and reduces and
诸如此类的事情。
things like that.
因此，在这里，我们可以映射事件流，在概念上与我们大致相同
So here, we can map over an event stream in much the same way conceptually that we
可以映射到已经完成的数组上。
could map over an array that was already complete.
只是每次有数据进来，
It's just that every time a piece of data comes through,
我们可以对它进行某种转化。
we can do some sort of transformation on it.
这里的转换是我提取类名
And here the transformation is I'm extracting the class name
从事件对象，好的。
from the event object, okay.
我们可以过滤下来，我们可以在我们的列表上执行排除。
We can filter down, we can do perform an exclusion on our list.
这是很有趣的事情。
And that's something interesting.
因为从根本上说，这个列表实际上是异步的。
Because fundamentally, fundamentally this list is actually asynchronous.
我们实际上可以在我们的响应中有异步的步骤。
We can actually have steps in our response that are asynchronous.
在改变之前是不同的。
Distinct until changed.
这是个有趣的故事。
It's an interesting one.
它说的是，当一条数据第一次通过时，让它通过。
What it says is, the first time a piece of data comes through, let it go through.
但是如果另一个通过相同的数据片段，不要让它通过
But if another one comes through the same piece of data, don't let that go through
因为我已经看过了，但是如果有新的事情出现。
because I've already seen that one, but then if something new comes along.
让那个通过。
Let that one through.
如果我一直收到同样的东西，
And if I keep getting the same one of those,
不要让更多的副本通过。
don't let any more duplicates come through.
所以让我们说，我有一个，第一个进入系统，然后
So let's say, I have one that the number one comes to the system and
我得到了五个，只有第一个会在接下来的四个中通过
I got five of those, only the first one is going to be let through in the next four
将被忽略。
going to be ignored.
然后两个人出现了。
And then a two comes along.
所以我会让前两个出现在任何重复的地方
So I'm going to let the first two come along at any duplicates
将被忽略。
are going to be ignored.
当另一个出现时会发生什么？
What happens when another one comes along?
我要让一个又一个通过
I'm going to let a one one more one come through and
然后忽略任何重复的内容，直到更改。
then ignore any duplicates that's what the until changed is.
所以有不同的，只是我只想要一个曾经的东西和不同的
So there's distinct which is just I only want one ever of the thing and distinct
直到CHANGED是不同的，然后每次出现新的值时我都会重置。
until changed is distinct, and then I reset every time a new value comes in.
我重置了我记得的东西。
I reset what I'm remembering.
所以你注意到，在这个链条中，并不是我的所有事件都会出现在第11行。
So you notice in this chain, not all of my events are going to make it to line 11.
这完全没问题，因为我们正在为自己设置数据流，
And that's totally okay, cuz we're setting ourselves up with a data flow,
就像我们在电子表格中一样。
just like we would in a spreadsheet.
订阅有点像链条的末端。
Subscribe is kind of like the end of the chain.
订阅是你基本上拥有的方式
Subscribe is how you basically have
对即将到来的任何事件的一种同步响应。
a sort of synchronous response to any events that are coming in.
所以还有更多的事情要做。
So there's more to it than that.
但你注意到基本上订阅有点像同步的东西。
But you notice that basically subscribe is kind of like a synchronous thing.
我不是在转换任何数据
I'm not transforming any data,
它可能不会真的出现在我的链条中间。
it's not really gonna show up in the middle of my chain, probably.
有点像在我链条的末端，当我和
It's kinda be at the end of my chain, it's when I and
最后，无论数据是什么，都可以通过其所有转换和
finally done with whatever the data is through all of its transformations and
过滤我得到了一些数据。
filterings I arrived at some data.
因此，在我的链的末尾，我订阅了一条数据
So at the end of my chain, I have a subscribe of a piece of data that comes
进去，我就可以安慰你了，把它记录下来。凯尔·辛普森：好的。
in and I can console.log it out. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Okay.
这是与观察者一起工作是什么样子的一个真正的高级视图。
That's a real high level view of what working with an observable is like.
我们必须以某种方式进行观察，我们有公用事业，而且
We have to make an observable some way and we have utilities, and
图书馆可以为我们做到这一点，然后我们必须对可观察到的东西做出反应。
libraries that can do that for us, and then we have to respond to observables.
我认为，有些人不同意这一点，这是恰当的，但是
And it's appropriate, I think, some people disagree with this, but
我认为把一个可观察到的东西想像成一条小溪是合适的。
I think it's appropriate to think of an observable as a stream.
这是一个即将到来的数据流。
It's a stream of data that's gonna come through.
它被一系列事件所激发，它是即将到来的数据流
It's being pumped by a set of events and it's a stream of data that's coming
通过。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以
through. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So
那么differtUntilChanged呢，我实际上希望你们都弹出这个。
what about distinctUntilChanged, I actually want you all to pop this up.
你在你的幻灯片中有链接或者你可以直接输入，
You have in your slides the link or you can just type,
我喜欢这个网站RxMarbles.com。
I love this website RxMarbles.com.
让我们一起来看看RxMarbles.com，我对这个网站很感兴趣
Let's all take a look at RxMarbles.com, I just get such a kick out of this web
站点。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：让我快速定位
site. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Let me quickly orient
你，继续往下点击difftUntilChanged，这只是
you, go ahead and click down on the distinctUntilChanged which is just
在左边的列表上稍微往下一点。
slightly down the list there on the left.
单击differtUntilChanged。
Click on the distinctUntilChanged.
你会注意到它描绘的是
And you'll notice that it's depicting for
给我们这些大理石，这些小气泡，
us what these marbles these little bubbles here,
有点确切地说，我们谈论的是触摸，顶部的东西就是输入。
kind of exactly we're talking about the touch the stuff on the top is the input.
而且只有一条河流可以做到这一点。
And there's only one stream for this.
底部的内容是输出。
And the stuff on the bottom is the output.
当我开始移动这些弹珠时，你会注意到发生了什么。
And you notice what happens, as I start to move these marbles around.
如果我把这个移动到这里会发生什么，固体
What happens if I move this one over here, the solid
只是消失了，因为序列意味着它只是一个副本。
just disappear because the sequence meant that it was just a duplicate.
所以我们可以移动弹珠
So we can move the marbles around and
查看这些不同的流操作是如何操作的。
see how these different stream operations operate.
我们将回到RxMarble并查看更多的流操作和
We're going to come back to RxMarbles and look at more stream operations and
有一点，但你可以注意到可能是在顶部。
a little bit, but you can notice that probably about the top.
我想说可能有30或40个在这里被描绘。
I'd say maybe 30 or 40 of them are depicted here.
RX实际上可能有150，
Rx actually has probably like 150,
可能有200种不同的方法，这是一个相当大的库。
maybe 200 different methods it's a pretty big library.
总而言之，如果你什么都有，我想大概是150，
All told, if you've got everything, I think it's something like 150,
200K的JavaScript。
200k of JavaScript.
所以这是一个相当结实的图书馆。
So it's a pretty stout library.
学习所有这些东西需要一段时间。
It takes a while to learn all these things.
我在网上找不到任何其他更好的学习资源
I have not found any other resource on the web that is better at learning
比起RxMarble，我认为你大概可以学习50%的观测值
than RxMarbles, I think you can probably learn probably 50% of Observables
什么都不做，只是在屏幕上玩泡泡。
by doing nothing but just playing around with the bubbles on the screen.
这是一个非常奇妙的资源。
It's a really fantastic resource.
好吧。
Okay.
帮助您直观地了解不同流操作发生的情况。
Helps you visualize what's happening with your different stream operations.
所以我们会回到DISTINCT直到改变，
So we'll come back to distinct until change,
我的意思是我们稍后会回到RX大理石上。
I mean we'll come back to RXmarbles here in a little bit.
我只是想向你指出这一点。
I just wanted to point that out to you.